<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Farr Projects</title>
    <link>/Projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew Farr Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 03:21:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/Projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/Projects/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 03:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Projects/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/resugary/hugo-theme-one&#34;&gt;One&lt;/a&gt; is a minimal blog theme for Hugo, which is forked from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/schollz/onetwothree&#34;&gt;onetwothree&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source code is released under the MIT license on GitHub. Feel free to use if you want to learn more or contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo!</title>
      <link>/Projects/posts/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 12:19:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Projects/posts/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hello from Hugo! If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this in your browser, good job! The file &lt;code&gt;content/post/hello-hugo.md&lt;/code&gt; has been converted into a complete HTML document by Hugo. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that pretty nifty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-section&#34;&gt;A Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple titled section where you can place whatever information you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use inline HTML if you want, but really there&amp;rsquo;s not much that Markdown can&amp;rsquo;t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;showing-off-with-markdown&#34;&gt;Showing off with Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full cheat sheet can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
or through &lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; examples for styling, though. I can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;emphasize&lt;/strong&gt; that enough.
Creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com/&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;code&gt;inline code&lt;/code&gt; blocks are very straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;There are some *easy* examples for styling, though. I can&#39;t **emphasize** that enough.
Creating [links](https://google.com/) or `inline code` blocks are very straightforward.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;front-matter-for-fun&#34;&gt;Front Matter for Fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the meta data for this post. It is located at the top of the &lt;code&gt;content/post/hello-hugo.md&lt;/code&gt; markdown file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
title: &amp;quot;Hello Hugo!&amp;quot;
description: &amp;quot;Saying &#39;Hello&#39; from Hugo&amp;quot;
date: &amp;quot;2014-09-01&amp;quot;
categories:
  - &amp;quot;example&amp;quot;
  - &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot;
tags:
  - &amp;quot;example&amp;quot;
  - &amp;quot;hugo&amp;quot;
  - &amp;quot;blog&amp;quot;
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section, called &amp;lsquo;Front Matter&amp;rsquo;, is what tells Hugo about the content in this file: the &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; of the item, the
&lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt; it was posted. In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ve added two custom bits of data too. The &lt;code&gt;categories&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; sections are used in this example for indexing/grouping content. You will learn more about what that means by
examining the code in this example and through reading the Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/introduction&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>/Projects/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Projects/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farr, M.T., Green, D.S., Holekamp, K.E., Roloff, G.J., and Zipkin, E.F. (In Review after Revision) Multi-species hierarchical modeling reveals variable responses of African carnivores to management alternatives. Ecological Applications.</title>
      <link>/Projects/posts/hmsds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Projects/posts/hmsds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://inr.oregonstate.edu/people/david-green&#34;&gt;David Green&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.holekamplab.org/&#34;&gt;Holekamp lab&lt;/a&gt; to quantify the impact of anthropogenic disturbance and management alternatives on the carnivore community within the Masai Mara National Reserve (MMNR), Kenya. Carnivore communities in the Serengeti-Mara ecosystem, including the MMNR, are among the most diverse in the world, but human-wildlife conflict threatens the continuation of this community. To understand the impact of anthropogenic disturbance on the carnivore community, we compare two disparate management regions within the MMNR that are managed by separate entities. The Mara Triangle experiences minimal disturbance while the Talek region contains high frequency of human-wildlife conflict. Using a hierarchical multi-species distance sampling model we estimate the community wide and species-specific effects of the Talek region on carnivore abundance and compared species’ abundances and group sizes between regions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farr, M.T., Green, D.S., Holekamp, K.E., and Zipkin, E.F. (In Prep) Integrating distance sampling with presence only data.</title>
      <link>/Projects/posts/isdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Projects/posts/isdm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am developing an integrated species distribution model that combines presence only data from opportunistic surveying with distance sampling. Species distribution modeling (SDM) uses ecological covariates and occurrence data to predict a species’ distribution. However, SDMs often return biased estimates due to imperfect detection and sampling bias, but model estimates can be improved by integrating more structured sampling into the model. I am working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://inr.oregonstate.edu/people/david-green&#34;&gt;David Green&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.holekamplab.org/&#34;&gt;Holekamp lab&lt;/a&gt; to demonstrate the use of ISDMs by combining presence only data and distance sampling to evaluate human disturbance and apex predator decline on black-backed jackal distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saunders, S.P., Farr, M.T., Wright, A.D., Bahlai, C.A., Ribeiro, J.W., Rossman, S., Sussman, A.L., Arnold, T.W., &amp; Zipkin E.F. (In Review) Disentangling data discrepancies and deficiencies with integrated population models.</title>
      <link>/Projects/posts/amwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Projects/posts/amwo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Zipkin lab is collaborating with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fwcb.cfans.umn.edu/personnel/todd-arnold&#34;&gt;Todd Arnold&lt;/a&gt; to use an integrated population model (IPM) to estimate population size and vital rates of the American woodcock (AMWO) using harvest data, band recovery data, and Singing Ground Surveys. We use an IPM framework to integrates multiple datatypes from AMWO and analyze them in conjunction. The results from our IPM reconcile discrepancies in inference from past studies that analyzed these datatypes independently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>